Long ago, there was a bird.
One day, the bird fell asleep while flying,
and a tragedy occurred.
It crashed into a long rock protruding from the ground.
The bird had a disease that would make it turn to stone upon crashing into a rock,
and it remained there, stuck, as eons passed by.
In some eras, it was an object of worship,
while in others, it was used as a drying rack.
While its use changed over the eras,
it became rooted to the area.
And now, in the present day...
This is the story of a city
that has nothing to do with that bird whatsoever.
Hello, dear my friends
I remember the days
We spent talking about our dreams
It's hard to become an adult
Let's go find the thing
That we kept hidden
Hey!
Throw away your cluttered mind
Swim in the clouds
Raise your head and run out, right
The rain has stopped
Sing along
Hold hands
I laugh too
You laugh too
I'm sure like this
We'll meet again
CLOSED
Big Bro, what's your star sign again?
Capricorn.
Yikes. Let me read you your horoscope.
This week for Capricorns—
Wait!
Don't lead with "yikes"!
Okay.
Then let me try again.
Try again?!
So, the ranking for Capricorns is...
You don't have to say it!
I don't believe in that stuff anyway!
Fine.
WEEKLY CITY MAGAZINE
Actually, I think you better tell me the lucky item!
CHAPTER HOUSE: "MAKABE FAMILY"
MAKABE'S WESTERN CUISINE
Is this really what it is?
Yeah. Says so right here. Miniskirt.
I see.
So, did it work?
Did what work?
Has this lucky item granted me luck now?
Who knows?
Well, I guess it has...
Yes, I've looked at it. It must have worked.
All right!
Wear it.
Wear it, Tatewaku.
Dad!
That's exactly what I didn't want to do!
Then what are you going to do?
I'll keep it with me all day and never let it leave my side!
What are you laughing at?!
Sorry, sorry.
Listen, Tatewaku.
If the lucky item had been curry rice,
what would you have done?
Would you just look at it all day?
Would you keep it on you all day and never let it leave your side?
You wouldn't, would you?
Tatewaku, curry is something you eat.
And a skirt
is something you wear.
You said you wanted to play in the next soccer match, right?
If the new girl we hired actually shows her face, you can go to the match.
But there is no guarantee she'll come.
So take the plunge, Tatewaku.
For your own luck!
So, what are you going to do?
What?! What are you laughing about? It's my lucky item!
Don't take pictures!
For Mom.
For Ecchan.
Don't send it to people!
Don't keep it as a memory!
Where were you even keeping that microphone?
Someone, help me!
STAFF ONLY
Wait, where'd they go?
When did they stop chasing me?
CITY SOUTH MIDDLE SCHOOL
Matsuri, if you could have only one special power, what would it be?
CHAPTER PAIR: "FRIENDS"
The ability to have money come out of my hands nonstop!
So greedy!
Well, what about you, Ecchan?
Me?
The ability to turn all of that money into counterfeit bills.
No fair! I'll get caught!
I won't let you take over the world that easily.
But Ecchan, that ability...
It'd be useless unless I was around.
So, you've finally noticed, Matsuri.
Who are you?
Good evening. I'm Ecchan.
Oh, good. It's just you, Ecchan.
Without you, my abilities won't manifest.
So the reason I chose that ability...
Do you know it?
I have no idea.
Think about it a little.
The thing I really want isn't an ability.
That's right.
Matsuri.
It's you.
Ecchan!
Marry me—
Rejection toss!
No sweat!
That's the Ecchan I know!
Not joining a club and watching sumo every day has served you well.
That's not true! I'm in the go home club!
I'm the go home club champion!
If you're the champion, what am I?
You're a go home club champion too!
Two champions!
Then shall we defend our titles today too?
We'll defend our titles and leave our mark on history!
ARASHIMA TEMPLE
We're almost at the farewell intersection.
Fifty yen. Let's get some juice.
Matsuri, what are you doing?
Imagining money coming out of my hands.
Stop it, Ecchan! Don't send out those vibrations!
SWEET OLIVE MANOR
I don't think I can go on any longer.
Please give me a break.
Come on, Sensei, you can do it!
Mr. Editor, I've gotten this far with nothing but bummer material,
but now...
I'm all out of ideas.
RESUME
NAGUMO MIDORI
MAKABE'S WESTERN CUISINE
Hello!
All right, then.
You're really going at it, huh?
Oh, you came at just the right time.
Take this over there.
Okay, okay.
Here, take this—
First player, giant pawn.
Second player, medium-sized gold.
CHAPTER RAMEN: "CRISPY NOODLES"
Ten seconds.
One, two, three, four, five, six...
It went in—
in—
Please! Pretend you didn't see!
What?! There's no way you can cover that up!
It went straight in!
Then what would you do?
Run away!
Ouch!
The owner can't just run away!
Then all we can do is apologize!
She's Right,
Obviously
Ouch!
She's Right,
Obviously
You bastard!
How naive can you be?
If I apologize,
he'll yell at me!
That's so obvious, it woke me right up.
Here, come here.
I can't say this out loud,
but there's no choice but to trick him.
Since I can't say it out loud...
He went on and on about his strategy,
but my ears were so fuzzy that I was incapable of doing anything...
AND SO:
OTTER PERIGNON
I bought a real good one!
All right, did you get the receipt?
It's in your wallet.
Great work.
So, are you ready?
IN CHARGE OF
CRISPY NOODLES
THE OWNER
IN CHARGE OF THE
WINE AND BAG
NAGUMO
This is getting pretty darn exciting!
Here we go.
"THIS IS ON THE HOUSE."
Sorry!
I am terribly sorry!
So sorry!
Sorry!
No words can possibly express our remorse!
What a delight!
I knew it was the right choice to build in a microphone.
SIZZLE
CRACKLE
KABOOM!
CHAPTER TASSEL: "DR. ADATARA"
No, no, please raise your heads.
Be at ease, both of you.
The reason the cork hit my forehead and that I got all wet
is because you were kind enough to offer me free champagne.
It left a dent...
Your thoughtfulness is most delightful.
It is only a small gesture,
but allow me to give this to you.
A Consideration Award.
This person hasn't noticed the crispy noodles.
I delivered the food.
Whoa! Why are you bowing down like that?
You really came! Thank you so much!
You honestly looked like a total flake on your resume,
so I was super worried.
Hey!
As embarrassing as it is, this is all thanks to wearing the miniskirt!
Well then, I'm going to continue my homework in my room—
room—
Hot! It's hot!
BOOM!
Why are there crispy noodles in my bag?!
So it was just Tatewaku's bag all along?
Good for you!
It's not good at all!
How the heck did two crispy noodles even get into my bag?!
Don't you understand, Tatewaku?
How the heck could I understand?!
For a brief moment, you wore a skirt.
But you quickly returned to wearing pants.
But!
In other words, that's how it goes.
This was destined to happen because you're not wearing your lucky item.
That's what you think! I'm still wearing it!
I feel like I've seen this course of events before.
Don't just go straight back to work!
Don't just go straight to eating!
Don't just go straight to taking the staff meal home!
If you're gonna make fun of me, do it right!
What the heck is this horoscope?
What part of this is supposed to be a lucky item?
SAUCE
BOOM!
ADATARA LIQUORS - BEER, SPIRITS, WINE
That place is smoking again.
CHAPTER HAT: "IZUMI WAKO"
Oh, no!
Oh, no, no, no...
No, no, no...
I think... This is...
totally one of those "lost my point card" situations!
I don't have a clue where I could've lost it,
so I'll sniff some Kaimei ink and calm myself down a bit.
Maybe it's because of this gentle, nostalgic scent,
but I find myself reflecting on my life so far.
NAME: IZUMI WAKO
These utterly average, unremarkable 20 years
are a bit depressing even to me.
At times like this,
I touch the gills on the underside of my beloved shiitake mushrooms to relax!
Academically speaking, it might possess an effect similar to drinking warm milk!
On a whim, I decide to stroke the surface of the shiitake mushroom too,
and am immediately captivated by its indescribable velvet-like texture.
Perhaps this fluttering feeling could take me somewhere interesting,
away from this ordinary daily life.
Just thinking about it makes my heart race.
To calm my overflowing emotions,
I touch the putty eraser I always keep in my pocket
and knead it at a steady pace.
Every part of the shiitake mushroom is precious.
Whatever the case may be,
I am grateful for this encounter.
Paru paru paru, point paru paru.
On a whim, I decide to chant a blessing,
hoping that my point card will appear.
"I'll make your wish come true."
Oh, God!
With such things running through my mind,
I get a good feeling that everything will just work out,
so I quickly start walking towards the police box.
OFFICER IS CURRENTLY AWAY
Reality is truly a cruel thing.
Excuse me.
Are you looking for this?
MAKABE'S WESTERN CUISINE
STAMP CARD
This is it, this is it!
It's been found all of a sudden!
Thank you, Officer!
That god I made yesterday really does have power.
I return to my room
and give the Papico packed into the tip as an offering to the god.
The bit of Papico stuck at the tip,
which I eat just before it melts,
is exceptionally delicious.
The main part is also delicious.
What if I add another layer of happiness to my current state of happiness?
Could it be that I'll become dangerously happy?
I stretch the putty eraser,
creating the fluffy spots that appear just before it breaks,
and begin tapping them gently.
The mystery of this cotton-like substance being formed from a hard putty eraser.
The bliss of crushing it all by myself.
This is truly the bestest,
the greatest, the happiest time of all.
However, this happiness is a different flavor,
which makes me realize that there are all kinds of different happinesses.
MR. BUMMER
REALITY IS
TRULY A CRUEL THING
A joke...
Anything...
A bummer joke...
We do have one ultimate trump card.
I'm going to say it!
This week will be the final chapter.
What?
I've... thought of something.
CHAPTER DOOR: "ROOM 203"
Hey.
Sorry!
Were you doing some sexy stuff?
No way!
I was taking a photo of broccoli!
Why did you come barging in here, anyway?
Well, you know, I got extra of the staff meal.
Betcha want some too, right, Niikura?
Thanks for the... food.
What's with that smirk on your face?
All right, that'll be a thousand yen!
Schemer!
CHAPTER SPARKLE:
Speaking of, how was your part-time job?
Well, listen to this.
Two servings of crispy noodles went straight in like, "whoosh!"
Wow, sounds like a busy day.
Something like that.
Niikura, what did you do?
I went to college.
You should show your face one of these times, Nagumo.
Like "whoosh"?
Like whoosh!
By the way, what were you doing with that broccoli earlier?
You want to know?
MITAKE CAMERA
Ta-da!
The magazine I bought this morning.
Here, take a look at this!
MICHAEL J. NIIKURA (AGE 18)
Yes. Me!
Amazing!
Seriously?
How much did you get for it?
Nothing. Zero yen.
Worthless.
Hey!
If you get the grand prize, it's 100,000. 100,000!
That's the dream, isn't it?
That's enough to cover two months' rent.
Show me the one that won the grand prize.
IZUMI WAKO (AGE 20)
No way!
Niikura, do they accept pictures taken with a cell phone?
Yeah, I don't think it's a problem.
Seriously? We can totally get the 100,000 yen!
W-What do you take your pictures with?
I use a normal square camera.
So plain!
All right, lend that to me!
Well, if it's for you...
All right!
However!
Please wait until the end of the month.
Once I get paid, I can use the money I've saved...
and buy a DSLR!
I worked super hard and saved up!
Until then, I'll take a bunch of pictures and submit them all!
That's amazing.
Niikura, it seems like you already know the thing you want to do.
W-Where's this coming from all of a sudden?
The thing that'll be your thing throughout your college days.
You've already found it.
It's just a bit of a shock.
Do you want to become a photographer in the future, then?
Well, if I could, that'd be great, but...
What's this all about?
Nagumo, don't you have a thing?
Something you want to do.
I mean, sure I do.
I'll help you too. Let's find it together...
Wait, you do?!
Then what was that whole spiel earlier?
What do you mean, "spiel"?
So, what is it? The thing you want to do.
Something fun.
Well, then I guess you should do something fun.
But there are so many things that I can't choose just one.
But if I'm gonna do something,
I wanna do the most fun thing of all!
Pu...
So pure!
"DREAM"
The season that was vague
Melts without a care
In just five minutes on foot
Down the sweltering street
Whether it's a dream or reality I can't tell
Oversleeping and ending up in a pinch
Endlessly chasing all things I want
Feeling embarrassed or being stubborn
They say now's the best time to eat them
Pretending to be the same as always
It's a summer
That's different from last year
Annoying, but still, it's fun
You're still you
In this town on the edge
Where everyone's the same
I want to be with you today too
Beyond the roof
The sun is hiding
Ah, summer is leaving