Well...
Land of the Lustrous
time for work.
Ah, right.
Phos! I know you're here!
Phos!
Master Adamant is looking for you.
Why is that?
Beats me.
Wait, you don't think...
maybe Master wants me to join you all in battle?
I highly doubt that.
I see even an ace like yourself is worried about what I might be capable of!
"Might  be capable of"?
Do you still not have a job?
Morga!
Goshe?
We don't have time for this!
There's sunspot activity in the sky to the south.
It's small, but we need to alert Master!
All right.
If it's small, let's just fight it off ourselves!
What?!
Don't go getting haughty!
It'll be fine!
We need to cut Master a break sometimes.
He's older than he looks after all.
You hurry on back now!
Jerk.
Acting busy and all that...
Okay!
Today's the day then.
Wait! Gotta make the right impression.
Perfect! Cute!
Dignified!
Phos is as lively as ever, huh?
I just hope he won't cause trouble.
Reporting!
Come.
You called for me, Master Adamant?
Yes.
Phosphophyllite, at last, I have a job for you.
Phosphophyllite
We can handle this.
Yeah.
Oh!
Master, just a little while ago, Morga and Goshe
said they saw one of the Lunarian sunspots.
But, since it was small, they said they'd...
Master?
What?!
That didn't stop it?!
And look at the color of those arrowheads...
Aren't those pieces from Heliodor's capture?
How could they do that?
It's perfect.
Let's take back every last piece!
They come to harvest us as jewelry.
While their hunters sweep down
in countless numbers from the moon,
there are but 28 of us.
The skilled among us work in pairs. Some keep lookout.
Some fight.
Each of us has our own skills which we use
to fulfill our goals and help one another.
But you seemed fit for none, and I was at a loss.
With your physical condition
and incomparable clumsiness,
I could find nothing to rely on you for.
Why not just have me fight then?
Fight, you say?
Well, I mean, that's the only thing we've never tried, right?
You would do best to give up on that.
Yikes.
Looking out for your elders, are you?
Here it comes! Fall back!
You're still incapable!
You fools!
Oh, dear.
You are particularly fragile,
and your hardness is only three and a half.
Simply brushing into someone
is more than enough to break you.
Moreover, the Lunarians are fond of your peppermint color.
To overcome all those weaknesses,
you would need to be able to wipe out
an entire army in one fell swoop.
You would need to be stronger than myself.
Like that'll happen!
Which is why I decided...
that you should compile our encyclopedia.
Wh—
What?!
You're gonna spill!
That's so boring!
Quite the contrary.
By compiling an encyclopedia, you will both
preserve the present and prepare for the future.
It is an important role which requires creativity and intelligence.
The key to battle is a keen eye.
If you wish to fight, first train your eyes through this task.
I know you're just trying to trick me into it!
Only you've got the guts to back sass Master.
Big talk for someone who doesn't ever do a thing around here.
Who asked you?!
But it is that very frankness of yours that is needed for this task.
I'm counting on you.
Need any help?
Nope.
You put my legs on backwards last time, so no thanks.
Hmph, haven't forgotten that, huh?
Hey! Stop!
Don't you have an encyclopedia to write?
No one's ever going to need it anyway, and it's just a pain to deal with!
Sounds like you!
Oh, shut up!
Tell me, Rutile...
What is it?
Helio's in pieces, but if we get them all back, you can reform him, right?
Of course.
Our bodies are home to microscopic
organisms called "inclusions," you see.
Thanks to them, even if we break into pieces,
as long as we collect enough parts, we can be put back together.
It's a wonderful characteristic of ours seen in no other living being.
But, because of that, we have grown completely incapable of letting anything go.
There you are. Good as new.
Let's head back out there then.
Watch it!
You're the one who would break if we bumped into each other, you three-and-a-half!
I'm quite used to it, O Great Seven.
Take me wi—
Absolutely not!
You have to!
If I hadn't told Master Adamant, the both
of you would be out on the moon right now!
Don't forget it!
Rutile, you sure you can't switch the hardness of his body for the hardness of his head?
Come on, just get me out of this lame job, would you?!
You really hate it that much, do you?
Of course! I want a cooler job!
Want to trade places then?
I'm not so pitiful as to take what doesn't belong to me...
is what you probably thought I'd say!
You were mistaken!
That's heavy, you know!
Maybe this will teach you a lesson.
I just finished putting you back together...
Thank goodness!
I didn't think you'd really take it!
Hey...
you were hoping it would hit me, weren't you?
You got me.
Jeez. All right.
Fine then.
My only friend here...
Land of the Lustrous
is you.
Right, so...
Let me guess: "What is an encyclopedia anyway?"
Woah, it's blank?!
Don't peek!
You were hard at work putting this off, huh?
I'm amazed.
No! I'm just working out a greater overall concept!
I heard that encyclopedias are supposed to categorize everything in nature itself.
Share your wisdom, Goshe!
Like how though?
Maybe recording all the bugs and plants along the shore?
Gonna need more than that.
We know all about the things we use, so maybe the things we don't use?
Almost there—give me more!
We aren't really that familiar with this stuff, sorry.
Lookouts like us always have our eyes on the skies...
Cinnabar might know though.
Cinnabar...
Why don't you go ask?
I can't do that!
I can't go up to him!
We've never even spoken!
But he might know more than us.
Anyway, good luck on your wild discoveries, Master Scholar.
Master Scholar...
All right!
Idiot.
Cinnabar, huh? Nope.
I should probably ask Master Adamant instead...
Nope, that'd be even worse.
Half a day of lecture at least.
Still, I'm not really getting anywhere on my own.
I wouldn't mind making some big new discovery though.
Okay!
The Master Scholar must be open to the opinions of others.
Huh? Something new?
I only know about the stuff I work with.
But, hey, I want to fix this chair,
so could you just hold that there?
Oh! Nice timing, Phos!
Can you model this for me?
I heard you're working on an encyclopedia...
We're running low on hemp this year,
so don't go wasting paper!
I know all about glues and powders, but you want
something no one has used before, huh?
Ah.
Cinnabar out on night watch
might know something if you ask.
Oh, come on!
Wouldn't you know more than anyone?
Are you just brushing me off
'cause you're busy, you quack?
Maybe your mouth is in need of an emergency operation.
Ew! Don't use that hand!
I mean, I know Cinnabar walks every nook
along the shore, but it's always at night, right?
Can Cinnabar even see anything?
The rest of us barely function at night.
Indeed, the rest of us feed off the sun and are not
built for the night, which makes things dangerous.
But Cinnabar...
Cinnabar's endless silvery poison pulls in the
faint night light and allows for patrols in the dark.
But...
The Lunarians have never shown themselves at night.
What? Then why even have a lookout at night?
No matter how unlikely, that is his job.
If you do go out there, be careful.
It's not like I want to go see him.
You probably know this already, but...
if any part of you comes in contact with his poison, light will no longer pass through it.
It will have to be chipped off of you.
And you will lose all the memories held within those chipped pieces.
Hey, you!
Quit wasting time on that useless job of yours
and help me discover something grand!
Wow! You'll let me help you, O Great Master Scholar?
Indeed.
And, just like that, I'll make Cinnabar my assistant.
Then I'll finish the encyclopedia, make some grand discovery,
earn everyone's admiration,
and then they'll realize I must have what it takes to join the battle.
Oh, yeah, that's it!
Benito!
Now, I do believe your room is right next to Cinnabar's.
Lead the way!
Why do you even wanna know?
He can't control his poison, you know?
Maybe it was just too much to bear,
but Cinnabar's been gone a long while now.
Benito, are you sure it wasn't because
you said something mean to my little helper?
Of course not!
Who do you think I am? You?
And what do you mean, your "helper"?
Give it up, Phos.
Poison is as natural as breathing to him,
and he knows to stay away from us
so he doesn't cause trouble.
But, honestly...
just being near Cinnabar leaves me uneasy.
Cinnabar's a bother just by existing...
Who'd have thought someone was
even more good-for-nothing than me?
I dunno why he'd do such a pointless, useless, thankless job.
Not at all.
Why not just quit?
Nowhere to be found.
Come on, help a Master Scholar out here.
Cinnabar, where are you?
If you aren't out on this cliff, that means you're either...
out in the ocean or up in the sk—
Why would anyone come at twilight, I wondered,
but of course it's you, Three-and-a-Half!
Damn...
Why now?
My breathing kills the grass and earth itself...
I don't want to ruin any more.
I don't want to be seen anymore.
Not like this...
I don't want to fight...
I don't want t—
Cinnabar!
I never asked for help.
Cinnabar...
I'm the weakest out of all 28 of us...
Hardness: two.
There.
I've chipped away all the contaminated spots.
Do you remember who I am?
A quack.
Perhaps it was worse than I thought.
Let's carve that right out of you.
An excellent doctor!
Well, that's the best I can do.
I've never had to be chipped before.
Have you forgotten anything?
I don't really know yet,
but I definitely won't forget today...
Cinnabar didn't want to fight, but still saved me.
Indeed. Quite shrewd.
Unfortunately, the area there is now stagnant.
The water, flora, and fauna will be of no use for some time.
Phos, the truth is...
Cinnabar is incredibly bright and gifted,
but, because his touch brings ruin, we have no way of handling it.
So we have forced him out into the night.
Is that all we can do?
Rigorous, meaningful work is the best medicine
against questioning one's place in the world.
We cannot die, so we must simply face these problems
as they are until we eventually find an answer.
Or perhaps you'll find a place for Cinnabar for us?
Aren't you looking for a big discovery?
How am I supposed to do that?
Even you and Master Adamant
couldn't think of anything else, right?
Tell me, though: where did
Cinnabar stay during the day?
Just sort of appeared when I went up that cliff to the north.
The Cape of Emptiness?
Yeah, there, at just the right moment.
The Cape of Emptiness is the most dangerous of locations and where Heliodor was stolen away from us.
I can't imagine Cinnabar would stay there long...
Oh, Phos.
Dia...
I'm glad to see you're well.
You must be careful out there.
Yeah...
I don't know.
I guess I might as well jot it down.
Hey.
Cinnabar...
Haven't you had enough already?
Th-This is my job! I'm not here by choice!
And why are you even here again anyway?
Helio got taken here! It's dangerous, you know?
It is.
And I...
I'm waiting here until I'm swept away.
At least on the moon they might make use of me.
I've been waiting, but they never come.
Yet, the second you arrive, they show up.
Must be nice.
Desired even by our enemy...
There are two species along the south beach.
Three species on the Twin Shores.
One in the Inter Plain.
One on White Hill.
I don't know if any are major discoveries,
but I've seen unnamed, unused plants out there.
Rutile came out to treat me this morning.
That's all you need from me, right?
Now stay out of my way.
I'd like you to help me!
I don't want to.
F-Fine!
Well, I'm going to find something more fun
than the night watch that only you can do then!
So just...
don't say you're leaving for the moon!
Got it?!
Hey.
Are you all right?
What then? What is it?
What can only you do?
I couldn't sleep 'cause something was flapping around,
and I find he left this here.
How careless can he get?
You big dummy.
Not my problem.
This handwriting is horrendous.
And these pictures are just as bad.
What's even in this?
I want to be free of the night.
But it won't happen. I refuse to believe him.
This stupid thing...
But, still...
I don't want you to go away.
nemuri no te
In the hand of sleep,
tojikomerareteita netsu ga
the passion that was locked away,
mizugiwa ni tadayotta sono iro
that color drifted on the shoreline
yukisaki wo wasurete
I forget where I'm going,
hibi ni toketa musuu no tsubu ga
my destination mixing
into the days like countless beads
yotsuyu uketomeru utsuwa
of evening dew catching into a bowl
kaketa hitokakera sagashiteru
I'm searching for the chipped fragment
Land of the Lustrous
yuudachi ga nazukerareta
sekai wo hagashita toki
When I tore myself away from the world that gave meaning to evening rain,
sore wa nami no you ni
it was like a wave
yubi no sukima wo surinukete kiete
that slips through
my fingers and disappears
katachi wo kae kurikaesu
yume dake ga
This constant dream of where I change
watashi wo tsunaideiru
is all that keeps me together
Diamond
Next Time