Please watch your step, Mr. President.
Freeze!!
Hands up and turn around!!
Shoot him!!
Hey!
Isn't this the Library?
No, it isn't...!
Blockheads.
Oh well... then I'll go on foot.
What are you?!
I-jin.
Created by Hideyuki Kurata
Development: Ryuzo Shirakawa
Producers: Masatoshi Fujimoto
Heiichi Matsuda
Original Character Idea: Taraku Uon
Anime Character Design:
Masafumi Ishihama
Mechanical Design: Eiji Suganuma
Production Design: Kunyuki Jinguji
Color Planning: Shinji Matsumoto
Art Director: Kazuo Ogura
Art Setting: Iho Narita
Director of Photography:
Shinyo Kondou
Music: Taku Iwasaki
Director: Kouji Masunari
Wake up!
Up! Up! Up!
Wake u
Up
up!
Up! Up!
Up!
Wake up!
Up! Up! Up!
Hello...
This is Readman.
Yes, Yomiko Readman...
Yes, I am.
Yes!
Washington Destroyed
Yes, I'm totally free!
Yes, that's fine.
You can count on me!
Just a moment please.
Clean up!
Up! Up! Up!
Yes, go ahead.
Yes...
Yes!
Yes, the twelfth, next week.
OK, the week after.
Not at all, thank you!
Thank you very much!
I did it!
Space Galaxy Commander
Save this up!
Up! Up! Up!
Eat this up!
Lock it up!
Up! Up! Up!
Most Important Customer
If you see her, say hello to her!
All Japan Book Association Tokyo Branch
unsterbliche Geliebte
Note: "Immortal Beloved", the addressee of a love letter which composer Ludwig van Beethoven wrote in July 1812.
Wait, don't take that.
Why?
I was going to buy that book.
But I'm the one who picked it up.
Well, then.
Can I get this?
3500 Yen.
Ah... I'm sorry, but could
I pay at the end of the month?
Immortal Beloved...
What? What is this?!
Bugs? What is this?!
I'll take that book!
Unmistakable.
What happened?
Please give my book back!
I just started reading that!
Give it back!
Am I too late!?
Yomiko!
Joker??
Yomiko! Why are you here?
You too Joker!?
Why are you here??
I see. It was you.
What in the world was that?
I'll explain later.
Yomiko... I mean, The Paper,
come with me.
Let me borrow that for a moment.
I haven't read it yet!
I'll return it after it's analyzed.
What is it really? Geez!
The world is in danger.
Hi, Joker. That was fast.
Paul.
Please take a look at this immediately.
OK.
You shine brightest
when surrounded by books.
Do... do I?
But, evidently you need
improvement in all other areas.
Gentleman is waiting for you.
Mr. Gentleman, I've brought The Paper.
Yomiko, eh?
It's been a long time.
You grew up.
Please allow me to
bring you up to speed.
Very well...
Well then.
Two days ago...
a mystery man appeared
in Washington DC.
He caused tremendous damage...
eventually attacking the
United States Library of Congress.
He stole six hundred
manuscripts and disappeared.
Manuscripts?
Yes.
We have received a formal request
from the US Library of Congress.
It's for capturing the offender
and returning the manuscripts.
However, this case
has bizarre elements.
Concerning this footage
of the mystery man...
In other words... It's about this...
The Elekiter, made by a Japanese
inventor named Gennai Hiraga.
Which is to say...
there's the possibility that
the mystery man is Hiraga Gennai.
But Hiraga Gennai died years ago.
Precisely...
A year ago, stem-cell samples
of I-jin were stolen...
from the Department
of Dominant Gene Conservation.
Hiraga Gennai's name is
on this list of stolen DNA.
Someone may have used this
DNA to bring Gennai back to life...
with dreadful special abilities.
For what purpose?
Unknown.
The entry in the grasshopper
guy's note book...
corresponds to Fabre's
"Book of insects".
That man is a clone
of Jean-Henri Fabre.
Why did Fabre attack me?
You were not his target,
the book was.
This is the first of two books.
The second book was
among the stolen manuscripts.
Gentleman, someone has concocted
an evil plot utilizing I-jin DNA.
Please devise an official operation
to settle this business.
All right.
Thank you very much.
Now, the British Library
Special Engineer Force...
shall commence
"Operation Manuscript Retrieval."
Excuse me, am I part of this, too?
Of course you are.
I... I have a substitute-teaching job...
as a maternity leave
replacement starting next week.
Which do you think is more important?
World peace or maternity leave?
But... but, even if the world was at peace,
without a job, I wouldn't be happy at all!
We'll pay for your services.
It's not enough!
I've been buying so
many books this month.
Oh, and I have an unpaid
balance on that book, also!
You haven't changed.
You're impetuous as usual.
OK, I'll give you the second volume of
that stolen book as an extra reward.
Really?
Yes.
I... I'll try my best!
Are you sure about that?
I can fake it.
What is it?
The book...
Analysis first.
Gentleman.
I would like to have a support
staff and one more agent.
Very well.
Drake Anderson speaking.
Now listen here!
I picked a paper fortune this morning!
It said "Great Fortune".
You know, that's big time lucky!
But half way through the day...
stupid Joker called me
and told me to support you!
If "Great Fortune"
gives me a day like this...
what kind of disaster would it have
been if I picked a bad fortune?
Ah... Drake!
It's a mission! Get down!
Oh... yes!
Mister Anderson, over here.
Poor thing...
What's wrong?
The damage to this wall is odd.
There's no residue of any
explosive or fire damage either.
Has the other agent arrived?
I don't know.
And?
Yes.
What should I do now?
Just don't bother anybody.
Go to a corner to sit
and daydream or something.
What do you mean?
This room appears to
have become a microwave.
Is it an Optical weapon?
Corner... corner...
Von Arnim's "Letters to the Assembly"!
This one is Pincinelli's
"Mundus Symbolicus"!
"Gustav Flaubert" is just sitting here.
You're...!
We meet again, The Paper.
Then, it's you!
I'm Miss Deep.
Deep?
I've been hearing rumors about you.
Though I was not expecting
to see you in Tokyo.
So you're after this book, too?
It was an order from Joker.
But I didn't think you were The Paper.
I'm Yomiko, Yomiko Readman.
I see.
What's your name?
I told you, I'm Miss Deep.
Your real name?
Are there any agents that give their
real names at a first meeting?
Yeah...
Your awareness is insufficient.
But, won't we get along better
calling each other by name?
We pair up for the mission.
Codenames are enough.
I see...
Well, nice to meet you for now.
Yes!
Huh?
This is my power.
I can dive deeply into substances
and pass through them.
That's why I am Deep.
You leave yourself wide open.
The Paper is no big threat.
I'm sorry... I was...
My glasses are...
So you do have some skills.
Huh?
I am Otto Lilienthal!
I'll take that book!
What?!
A bullet can't kill the wind!
You can never kill the wind!
What a bad day...
Drake!
He took the book!
Huh?
I'll go after him!
The enemy was one of the I-jin,
report it!
Who is this?
Oh, my partner...
Miss Deep.
What's your fortune today?
Huh?
Malone from the FBI.
Connect me to the Pentagon.
Come in.
I brought the data.
I-jin have been spotted!
This one's name is "Otto Lilienthal".
Who is that?
He was called,
"the Aerial King of Germany".
Mister Gentleman?!
An obscure genius during
the glider generation.
That genius is heading to New York.
At phenomenal speed!
Echo 1, 2, 3. We spotted the target,
an unidentified flying object.
Shoot him down!
They're flying such pedestrian crafts.
Still one left, eh?
Echo 1, 2 and 3 shot down.
The US army is having a hard time.
You can't fight him conventionally.
My book...
All units converge on target.
All units, prepare for battle!
Fire as soon as you have a visual.
A Samurai?!
All... destroyed!
Bail out!
What can we do?
We can't catch him on foot.
I know.
But there must be some way...
There is a way!
You're going after him in that?
Seriously?
Unbelievable...
Hurry!
Take this.
I've never had a mission like this.
Don't blame me if you fall off!
I'll blame you!
Three...
Two...
One...
Fire!!
That woman is misfortune.
Hey! What's going on?
Sorry! I forgot the tail assembly!
Successful takeoff!
I thought it was falling.
It's about time to go back... mm?
Please give my book back!
Land slowly, now!
Don't underestimate me!
I'll show you why I was called
"The Aerial King"!
Flying in that thing! How shameless!
This is ridiculous!
He's up to something!
Spin! Spin!!
Crash!!
Hold on!
This sucks!
I am not happy!
Ms. Deep! I'm changing tactics!
Ok, I'm going.
Please!
Fall! Fall!
Eat some dust!
You...!
Witch!!
If you're a witch you
should fly with a broom.
What?!
My book. Please give it back!
Give it back to me!
You...!!
Paper...
The book...
Die! Die!
Your sky comes to a dead end here.
Die!!
The book!
You're an idiot, aren't you?
Don't you ever think
about the consequences?
Is that book more
important than your life?
But at least you're not
a useless idiot, after all.
Thank you very much Miss Dee...
Nancy. Nancy Makuhari.
Eh? But...
It's fine now.
To be honest, I hate that codename.
It's not cute at all.
I'm Yomiko, Yomiko Readman.
I heard that before.
He was a blockhead,
even on the verge of death.
Oh well, let's report back.