You seem to be making
quite the assumption.
Did you think that against Prince Julius...
I would hesitate?
This is all for the greater good.
Don't take it personally, Prince Julius!
Still showing your legs
in that unbecoming manner, I see.
Very impressive, Prince Julius.
Even when you break your wrist,
you heal it immediately with a spell.
You do indeed have
the advantage in close combat.
Acceleration: Three Burst.
He predicted it?
What the hell?
Her prince abandoned her
and even attacked her, and yet...
I want you in greater despair!
You really are a heartless woman.
You actually punched
your own kingdom's prince!
It's awful to hear you say I'm heartless.
This is proof of true love...
The fists of love that won't stop until
Prince Julius is back in his right mind!
May I Ask For One Final Thing?
I hate people who look down on me
because they're life's winners.
Always enjoying themselves...
No way!
Sorry!
Who was that?
You okay?
Like they never act petty
or think awful things.
I...
I want to see them in despair.
I want their faces distorted with agony.
Still, this isn't like you.
To fall straight into the enemy's trap...
Fireball, blaze with an inferno's rage.
Or is it that you prefer
women like Terenezza?
Jealous?
It's rather charming to see you
act like a lady your age for once.
Stop flirting already.
Do you not realize the situation you're in?
That's a good look on you, Scarlet.
I should have just done this from the start!
I can see your blessing exhausting itself.
It's really weak now!
In that state, you won't
be able to stop my lance.
If you don't want to see
your precious prince killed,
surrender where you stand!
Very well.
I admit defeat.
Link your hands behind your head.
This spell will steal
your blessings from you.
Blessings given directly by gods
can only be stolen with this special
spell that uses Palmia's power.
But if I steal your blessings,
I can achieve Palmia's goal with ease.
This spell has the power to prevent
a blessing from activating.
There's no way around this.
Julius, restrain her.
What inappropriate nonsense is this?
I'm restraining you.
Blame Terenezza, not me.
Seems my charm's effect is waning.
How truly vexing that blessing
of yours, Heroic Tale, is.
Heroic Tale?
You didn't know?
Well, it'll be mine soon enough.
I just know what Palmia told me,
but since this is almost over, I'll tell you.
Heroic Tale is a special blessing created by
Origin the Creator, the god above all others.
It allows the wielder
to unleash unlimited power
when the person they love is in danger.
The person they love?
No, I don't feel that way
about you whatsoever.
You deny it so earnestly...
But then why is the blessing
going into effect?
It's quite annoying, you know.
The way you toy with my feelings
with those suggestive acts of yours...
I don't have any of those feelings
for you, either.
Yes. That's right.
She really is cold!
Such an awful thing to say
to the person who threw himself on you
to protect you from Godwin's shot!
I like it, though.
Heroic Tale can't activate fully
unless the love is mutual.
That time back then, too...
Was that also the effect of
Origin the Creator's blessing?
Then the reason Julius almost died...
The reason he's doing what
that filthy woman says...
I guess it was always a one-sided love!
So funny!
It was all my fault? Because I didn't...
You really are a villainess!
You can never become a true leading lady!
Prince Julius.
Allow me to confirm one thing.
Yes?
If your blessing activates fully,
you'll be able to overcome all dangers
and save me?
Even under the influence
of the charm blessing...
Why are you asking me that?
Neither of us is in love with the other.
Well? Tell me clearly!
Yes.
Heroic Tale grants the power
to overcome all dangers
so I can save the one I love.
That's quite a relief.
Save me, Prince Julius.
It's finally broken.
Heroic Tale has activated completely?!
When you said you didn't feel that way
about me, you had me rather worried.
Huh?
I beg your pardon?
Do you know how much I struggled with
myself to work up the courage to say that?
You did well, though.
You can leave the rest to me.
Screw your Heroic Tale...
That nonsense doesn't stand
a chance against my divine vessel!
It's pointless.
Hit him! Just hit him!
Your divine vessel can't emit
anything more than a gentle breeze.
That gutless goddess Palmia
has a cruel sense of humor.
You don't get to say that!
You...
Die!
Quite a live wire you are.
You're smiling, black-hearted prince.
Why...
Why?!
Why won't anything go the way I want?!
I'm the leading lady!
I'm the main character!
Everyone's supposed to love me!
Everyone who doesn't
love me should just die!
The whole kingdom... the whole world...
should just disappear!
You show yourself at last,
you piece of shit goddess.
Don't worry, my darling Terenezza.
You have me to love you.
Now, show those villains
who try to get in your way
the true power of a leading lady!
Light of love, rain down.
What the...
Hey!
The ceiling's coming down!
Saint Protective Barrier!
I'll protect them all!
That would have fried us
if it had hit head-on.
Incredible power.
Yet your blessing, Heroic Tale,
nullified it entirely.
Quite impressive.
But she seems to have used too much power.
I believe it may be time
for us to strike back.
I believe it worked like this...
Light of love, rain down.
Would you like another helping of my fists?
She's regenerating as soon as she's injured...
Those necklaces don't even compare.
In other words, I can
punch her as much as I like?
No, I doubt the fun will last much longer.
As compatible as they may be,
a human vessel can't withstand
the power of a god for long.
Terenezza will die within minutes.
We have no way to finish her, so we
could wait for her to self-destruct...
I won't wait.
I won't let it end that way.
I refuse to.
Because...
I still haven't dealt her the blow
that will really make me feel better.
I thought you would say that.
I'll protect you with my blessing.
I'll make sure it holds out
until you can deliver that punch.
I won't say thank you.
I expect you to spend your life repaying me
for gifting you my maiden lips.
Go on, then.
Light of love, rain down.
Shine of the hero, protect my beloved.
If not... If not for you...
Scarlet!
Time, stop.
Time of Chronoir.
I shall now deliver...
the blow that will put all regrets to rest!
Go flying...
to the ends of the world!
I feel so much better now!
Blessing of Chronoa:
Saint Protective Barrier.
Did I do it?
Well done.
You carried out your duty perfectly...
Saint Sanya.
Yeah!
You're going to leave
without saying goodbye?
Prince Julius told me...
You've become an intelligence
agent for Pallistan, then?
Oh, well...
He said that if I didn't agree,
he'd sentence me to a hundred years
of hard labor in the boonies
with the other inquisitors!
It was basically a plea bargain!
There's no telling
when you'll return to Pallistan.
Dios!
I want to talk to you.
About us.
You heard that we were half-siblings, then?
You saved me in the western ruins that day.
Thank you.
In the past, I've only done my duties
as a saint because I was told to.
Because I thought it was
the only thing I was good for.
But...
Things will be different now.
I want to protect the people
of this country of my own will.
For the sake of this kingdom's future,
I want to carry out my mission
with my divinely granted gift,
risking my life to fight like you all do.
Scarlet was right. Sanya is strong.
Look at you...
Acting all grown up, are we?!
Hey! What are you doing?!
By the way, I told everyone that you only
betrayed them because I manipulated you.
Huh? But it was my own weakness that—
And anyway, the info you gave me
turned out to be meaningless!
I mean, when you told me with a straight face
about the taste of the bread you order,
it was all I could do to keep from laughing.
D-Dios!
Well, goodbye!
Next time we meet,
let's have ourselves a date, Scarlet!
Stupid Dios! Don't hit on my sister!
Farewell!
Never come back,
you lying elf!
If things go as planned, we should make it
well in time for Julius's tea party.
I believe it's to celebrate our contributions.
Saint Diana, Sir Sigurd, and the members
of the Holy Order will also attend.
Yes.
Once Terenezza was off the board,
the Eldrand Army withdrew immediately.
Things have finally been resolved.
But I fear how capable that man is.
He used the fact that he was
also controlled by her charms
as testimony to condemn
Sargon and the other Palmians.
In that moment, the Palmians saw clearly
that Diana was not a false saint,
and began to insist that they had been
brainwashed by the Saint of Palmia.
As a result, the Palmian religion
has been dissolved.
My brother, did you know
about Prince Julius's blessing?
I knew he had a blessing,
but for some reason he said...
I could never speak of something
so embarrassing in public.
...and kept it strictly to himself.
Even if he'd told me, though,
I'm not sure I would have believed it.
I don't even know how much of this he planned.
Indeed, how much did he plan?
Oh.
What is it, Scarlet?
You aren't feeling well?
He beat me.
He arranged a situation
in which I would be in danger
and have to rely on his power,
made me confess my feelings and kiss him...
In other words, to unlock his hidden power,
he intentionally let himself be charmed.
What are you muttering about?
Brother.
I have business to take care of.
I'll go ahead of you with Rex.
Such cute desserts!
Is this apple pie?
Scarlet's favorite.
We made a promise to have some
when this was all over.
Good day to you...
Prince Julius.
Perfect timing, Scarlet.
Your apple pie with vanilla
ice cream was just finished.
No, it is not yet finished.
It's lacking a dash of mortal peril, you see.
It seems you have something to say.
Yes.
Kindly brace yourself
so that I may enlighten you.
Ah, of course.
First, may I ask you one thing?
What is it?
When you kiss someone, you should be sure
to tilt your head just a little bit.
You don't want to bump noses.
Also, it's not good to dive in too quickly.
It hurts when your teeth clack together.
Next time we do it, I hope you'll
take these things into account.
Understand?
My beloved Lady of Beatings.
First, you said it was just one thing,
but you ended up making
two different requests.
Yes, I did!
Then may I also ask one final thing?
May I send this insensitive
black-hearted prince flying?
Wait, Scarle—
Translation
Subtitle Timing
Subtitle Editing
Quality Check
Translation Check
Elizabeth Ellis
Mariana Martinez
Meagan Smith
William Haggard
Sriram Gurunathan