Lighting a beacon of hope
at the journey's end
Walking on instinct, ignoring the noise
Searching for the real thing,
though admittedly a little uncertain
I chase after your shadow
Win or lose, it was all-or-nothing
This game of moral justice,
good and evil
Two sides of the same coin,
entangled in rules
Flames wrapped in righteousness
"Only God knows our fate"
That's just a coward's way out
If you're going to bear a grudge,
then be ready
If you've made up your mind,
see it through
Yeah, shake it off, shake it off
Let all this absurdity shatter to pieces
Beyond the inner conflict,
my thoughts are with you
As the days flow by
I hear the voices of my friends
racing through my mind
In the sound of impermanence
echoing all around
Living in chaos, mad and unrestrained
My heart's fate,
drawn at random like an Amidakuji
In times of turmoil, whenever they come
Each wound I bear is proof of our bond
Wear them with pride
Oh oh oh ohh
This is what a life worth loving
looks like
Yeah, shake it off, shake it off
Let all this absurdity shatter to pieces
Beyond the inner conflict,
my thoughts are with you
As the days flow by
I hear the voices of my friends
racing through my mind
In the sound of impermanence
echoing all around
MY FRIEND
That idiot. What's he thinking?
Conjuring multiple guns isn't easy.
It's like the "dominant hand rule."
A         A
Try writing with your nondominant hand.
It's never neat. Same principle.
It's only natural
he can't get the hang of it right away.
For a weapon-materialization type
like him,
he's gotta train with handling
multiple real weapons first
before trying to control
multiple blood weapons at once.
Even then, it takes insane
mental strength, focus, and imagination.
Six guns at once, though?
Gives me chills.
Shiki Ichinose isn't the kind of guy
who fights with his head.
You can multiply zero brains
by anything.
It still comes out zero.
If he tries copying a genius,
he's gonna die.
This is really bad.
I can't feel my right arm!
His regeneration can't keep up.
Maybe this is where he hits his limit.
I've gotta regroup.
How the hell do I—
No, I just need to move, anything!
I told you, didn't I?
You're weak.
This outcome was inevitable.
Farewell.
Your heartbeat's melody ends here.
Huh?
Am I dying?
Why the hell am I trying this hard?
Why am I even trying
to pull out another gun?
I don't need to copy Mikado to fight.
I just have to do it my own way.
No, that's not it.
I know.
I... look up to Mikado.
I admire his strength.
Man...
I wish I could be like you, too.
If I were, things wouldn't have
turned out this damn pathetic.
If I were stronger, I could stop more
kids like Mei from ending up like that.
Even my dad...
he wouldn't have had to die.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's it!
I just wanna be stronger!
Like Mikado...
No.
Stronger than Mikado!
This is...
Getting to meet someone like you,
someone who made me feel this way,
seriously, I'm a happy guy!
So this is... Enki.
That guy...
he just materialized two guns.
Sure, the power of Enki
is backing him up...
but once you get the hang of it,
you've got it for good.
Let's see where this goes next.
When Mikado pointed his gun at me,
I realized something.
His weapons were crafted
down to the smallest detail.
To make something real,
you've gotta picture it piece by piece,
as if you're building it from scratch.
Never thought all those times I took
apart airsoft guns would pay off here.
But I'm still stuck at two guns,
damn it.
Face to face, I can feel it on my skin.
An overwhelming pressure,
like my blood's about to boil.
But so what?
That's no reason to run!
Block it like your life depends on it!
'Cause you'll die if you don't!
It feels like I'm burning
from both inside and out.
If I underestimate him,
I'll be turned to ash.
From here on out, I'm going all-in!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I must have been so weak,
it bored you, huh?
Now we can fight as equals.
Equals?
My friend...
don't you dare die on me!
Don't make me laugh!
You're out of your league!
In a gunfight, meeting head-on
in a straight line isn't ideal...
so...
I'll attack
from an angle you can't reach!
How? How are you up there?
He's melted the concrete with his heat
and jammed his feet right into it.
Now I can pull that off, too!
The power's incredible, but...
...your output's so huge,
it makes your trajectory easy to read.
You're kidding me!
Which means it's easy to dodge!
He's right. There's got to be
balance between strength and control.
Can I even do that?
Yeah, I can!
All I did was picture every detail,
and now all these images
are flooding into my head!
I can do this.
I can do this!
I can do it!
Even holding back, that power's amazing.
And those flames, what a nuisance.
He's developing fast.
Thinkers pick things up quickly,
but they take time to master them.
Meanwhile, instinctive types
take longer to grasp the basics.
But once they do, they adapt fast,
especially when it's a friend
who spurs it on.
Hell yeah! How's that?
Nothing to get cocky about.
An RPG?
Oh, crap!
This is seriously bad!
Close one.
A homing type?
No response.
He shouldn't be dead from a single hit.
Did he aim short on purpose?
Shit! I'm fallin'!
Damn it!
Let go of that!
Weirdly enough,
this fight ain't half bad, huh?
Feels like I've still
got more left to give.
Laughing in the middle of a fight.
You're insane.
What are you talking about?
Mikado Momodera had always
been cool and detached.
His strength had never once
made him burn with passion.
And then, one day,
Shiki Ichinose appeared before him.
Without a doubt, this man
would set Mikado's heart ablaze.
You're smilin', too, aren't you?
Hey, Mikado.
When I'm with you,
I feel like I can keep growin' stronger.
I wanna be that kind of person
for you, too.
Uh-oh.
He's going berserk?
So heavy...
He's on a whole different level
from before.
There's no opening to counter.
It's unlike any other Oni's rampage.
Pure, mindless slaughter.
This is an Oni?
No. This is a demon!
Looks like the Kishin power
went over capacity.
Even with my full defense,
this much damage...
Is this as far as I go?
Mikado...
kill... me.
Or else... I'll... kill... you.
Kill me...
before I... lose it... completely.
Please... hurry.
He's still conscious?
I don't wanna...
kill my friend.
Kill... me!
Hey, dumbass Momo, listen up.
I'll draw Ichinose away.
In the meantime, haul your
wrecked body up and finish this.
The worst-case scenario
is he goes down into the city.
Civilians will die.
I don't care what you think.
Get up and blast him.
Shoot like you mean to kill him.
Otherwise you won't stop him.
But if you really do kill Ichinose,
I'll kill you.
You're contradicting yourself.
But you're right.
We can't involve civilians.
In this condition, I need to prep.
Give me five minutes.
Get ready quick.
We don't have time to waste.
You don't need to tell me.
But I can't promise
you won't catch flak, too.
Cocky for someone
who's got one foot in the grave.
Well, then, let's see how far
a so-called noncombatant can go.
This is gonna sting.
Bring it on, brat!
Can you see me with those peepers?
Damn. Can't even get close.
Guess I'll focus
on keeping his attention.
Still, though...
it's cruel.
To still be conscious
while in a berserk state.
Run... away.
I really... will... kill you.
It'd probably be easier if you'd just
give in to the rage and black out.
But that willpower of yours,
that stubborn fight
against losing yourself...
Run... away.
...I won't let it be in vain, jackass.
I've never heard of an Oni
in berserk mode still being conscious!
He's crying.
Berserk Oni are supposed
to be mindless weapons.
Killing them is the right thing to do,
or so I thought.
Then why is he crying?
Doesn't that mean
he still has awareness? Feelings?
Could it be all the Oni
I've killed before...
were crying, too?
Then how much pain must that be...
wanting not to hurt anyone,
yet ending up hurting
everyone around you?
Even through that pain...
you still worried about me.
Even as you cried...
You've always been so honest
and so kind.
I don't wanna...
kill my friend.
Even after losing himself...
he still called me his friend.
I'm such a fool!
It must hurt.
It must be unbearable.
Ichinose...
No, Shiki!
I'll end your suffering
with my own hands.
Unreal.
Even when I disappear from sight,
he tracks me with his other senses.
Shit!
You've gotta be kidding me.
Damn it.
Of all things, my leg.
What a pain in the ass.
If he takes him out,
he'll come for me next.
What do I do? I'm still not ready.
The more I think about it,
the more hopeless it feels.
This is why I hate babysitting kids.
Run.
I'm a disgrace.
Ichinose...
don't feel guilty about my death.
What's with that peaceful look?
You planning to retire
to the afterlife already?
Sorry I'm late.
Your dramatic entrance pisses me off.
No need for a status report.
I've got a pretty good idea
what's going on.
So when are you planning
to fire that thing?
Showing up out of nowhere
and acting all high and mighty, huh?
I'm ready.
Fire...
I have to fire.
There's no way to save him except death
to free him from his pain.
At least let it be by my hand!
Mi...
Mikado...
Feeling this way makes me
a failure as a Momotaro.
But I don't care anymore.
Momotaro, Oni, none of that matters!
This is the will of me,
Mikado Momodera, as a person!
Please.
Please...
don't die!
Don't die!
Don't you die on me!
Thank... you.
Sure.
Action!
Harahara hara
Hey
Oh oh oh
Harahara hara
Hey
Oh oh oh
A moonlit night
Tonight is
the ultimate voltage
Our meeting
was so emotional
Oh oh oh
I always figured we'd
face off like this one day
Oh, give me
your words
Even if I believe,
there's no going back
Oh, before I fall
head over heels for you
Dive me out
Last dance
Let's dive deep into love
I want to try dancing with you
Is it already checkmate?
This charming little sparring match
Good or evil, none of it matters
Harahara hara
Hey
Harahara
- Do you think
- Hara
- I'm so crazy?
- Oh oh oh
Harahara hara
Hey
Harahara
- Do you think I'm so crazy?
- Hara oh oh oh
NEXT TIME
UNTIL WE MEET AGAIN